Guide to the Bryant Holsenbeck papers, 1978-2015 and undated RL.11849
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Bryant Holsenbeck papers
1978-2015 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Holsenbeck, Bryant
RL.11849
3.0 Linear Feet
This collection documents the work of the Durham, NC environmental artist Bryant Holsenbeck. It contains materials collected over the course of her career, including media clippings, publicity, photographs, and a portfolio.
Biographical / Historical
Bryant Holsenbeck is an environmental artist, activist, and author based in Durham, NC.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Bryant Holsenbeck papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2015.
Collection Overview
This collection includes gallery materials, correspondence, postcards, publicity materials, exhibit posters, clippings about Bryant Holsenbeck, documentation of Holsenbeck's work, photographs, a DVD production about Holsenbeck, and an art portfolio.
Recycling (Waste, etc.) in Art; Refuse as art material; Women artists -- North Carolina; Holsenbeck, Bryant; Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
- Gallery Correspondence, 1984-2001 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Gallery Correspondence: Mindscape, 1982-1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Exhibit Catalogs, 1980-2015 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Promotional Materials (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Exhibit Postcards, 1987-2015 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Clippings About Holsenbeck, 1983-2013; 4 folders (Box 1, Folder 6-9)
- Thank You Letters, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Arrowmont School, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Basketmaker's Art Book: Photocopies, undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Bottlecap Mandala at Duke, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Compos Mentis Booklet, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Headlands Center for the Arts, 1991-1992 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Miriam Schapiro, 1984-1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Natural Selection: Visitor Comments and Related Files, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Nine From North Carolina, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Pauli Murray Day, 2011 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Sunshares, 1993-1996 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Recycling Calendar with Holsenbeck's Art, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Photographs, 1978-1992 (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Album of Copied Photographs of Art, undated (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Blackbirds, Bottlecaps, & Broken Records: Environmental Artist Bryant Holsenbeck at Work DVD, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Away and Back Again DVD, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Make Garbage Disappear Box (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Art Portfolio (Box 2)
- Exhibit Posters (Box 2)